Guide to the Albert Gailord Hart Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Albert Gailord Hart Papers,
1925-1980
Hart, Albert Gailord, 1909-1997.
34 linear ft (ca. 14,800 items in 81 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library,
4079532
History
Professor of economics at Columbia University since 1946 and a consultant at the U.N. and other organizations.
Scope and Content
There are files of correspondence and papers of other economists and of his students, his research papers and professional publications, a group of published and unpublished papers dealing with the "Graham Plan" (Benjamin Graham, a securities analyst) for basing a monetary standard on a "basket" of primary commodities, and also the research notes of his work for the U.N. on Central America and tax reform in Chile. The teaching materials are accompanied by notes by Hart that describe the papers and relate them to the events of his life and thinking. The section headings in these notes correspond to the major divisions of the teaching materials.Among the correspondents are: Milton Friedman, J.K. Galbraith, A.B. Hart, J.M. Keynes, David Rockefeller, and F.W. Taussig.
Arrangement
Selected materials cataloged; remainder arranged.
Subjects
Columbia University.--Dept. of Economics.; United Nations.; Douglas, Paul H. (Paul Howard), 1892-1976.; Friedman, Milton, 1912-2006.; Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1908-2006.; Graham, Benjamin, 1894-1976.; Hart, Albert Bushnell, 1854-1943.; Keynes, John Maynard, 1883-1946.; Myrdal, Gunnar, 1898-1987.; Rockefeller, David, 1915-; Taussig, F. W. (Frank William), 1859-1940.; Central America.; Chile.; Consultants--United Nations.; Economics.; Economists.; Taxation--Chile.; Taxation--Law and legislation--Chile.; Notes.; Reports.; Graham plan.; College teachers.; Economists.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
1972 M-1972 Hart, A.G. Gift
Gift of Albert G. Hart, 1972, 1982, 1985, & 1986.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Blivens Bruce (Box 1)
  - Burns, Arthur F. (Box 1)
  - Clark, John Maurice (Box 1)
  - Commager, Henry Steele (Box 1)
  - Douglas, Paul Howard (Box 1)
  - Fisher, Irving (Box 1)
  - Friedman, Milton (Box 1)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth (Box 1)
  - Hart, Albert Bushnell (Box 1)
  - Hart, Hastings Hornell (Box 1)
  - Javits, Jacob Koppel (Box 1)
  - Keynes, John Maynard (Box 1)
  - Knox, Frank (Box 1)
  - La Follette, Robert Marion (Box 1)
  - Lippmann, Walter (Box 1)
  - Lovell, Abbott Lawrence (Box 1)
  - Mendes France, Pierre (Box 1)
  - Morgenthau, Henry (Box 1)
  - Myrdal, Gunnar (Box 1)
  - Nevins, Allan (Box 1)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold (Box 1)
  - Rockefeller, David (Box 1)
  - Ruml, Beardsley (Box 1)
  - Sachs, Alexander (Box 1)
  - Samuelson, Paul Anthony (Box 1)
  - Taussig, Frank William (Box 1)
- Series II: Uncataloged correspondence:
  - A -misc. (Box 2)
  - Agosin, Manuel R. (Box 2)
  - Albrecht, James W. (Box 2)
  - Allen, Edwrd D. (Box 2)
  - The American Assembly - Graduate School of Business - Columbia University (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Jean (Box 2)
  - Angell, James W. (Box 2)
  - Arrow, Kenneth Joseph (Box 2)
  - Atlee, John S. (Box 2)
  - B -misc. (Box 2)
  - Bach, George Leland (Box 2)
  - Barger, Harold (Box 2)
  - Barzun, Jacques (Box 2)
  - Bayer, Hans (Box 2)
  - Beck, Morris (Box 2)
  - Benoit, Emile (Emile Benoit-Smullyan) (Box 2)
  - Benson, George Charles Sumner (Box 2)
  - Berger-Voesendorf, Alfred Viktor (Box 2)
  - Bergeron, Lorenzo U. (Box 2)
  - Bernard, Philippe (Box 2)
  - Bernstein, Peter L. (Box 2)
  - Bird, Richard M. (Box 2)
  - Blackman, Courtney Newlands McLaurin (Box 2)
  - Bloch, Henry Simon (Box 2)
  - Blough, Roy (Box 2)
  - Bodt, Jean-Pierre de (Box 3)
  - Boeniger, Edgardo (Box 3)
  - Bogan, Elizabeth Chapin (Box 3)
  - Bonbright, James Cummings (Box 3)
  - Boreteky, Michael (Box 3)
  - Bossio Rotondo, Juan Carlos (Box 3)
  - Bossons, John (Box 3)
  - Boulding, Kenneth Ewart (Box 3)
  - Bowen, Howard Rothmann (Box 3)
  - Bramwell, Willis K., Jr. (Box 3)
  - Brontenbrenner, Martin (Box 3)
  - Brown, E. Cary (Box 3)
  - Brown, Owen (Box 3)
  - Brownlee, Oswald H. (Box 3)
  - Brunner, Edmund de Schweinitz (Box 3)
  - Bryce, Robert B. (Box 3)
  - Burns, Arthur F. (Box 3)
  - Burns, Arthur Robert (Box 3)
  - Burns, Elveline Mabel Richardson (Box 3)
  - Butler, William F. (Box 3)
  - Bye, Maurice (Box 3)
  - C - misc. (Box 3)
  - Cagan, Philip David (Box 3)
  - Campbell, Douglas Argyle (Box 3)
  - Caplan, Benjamin (Box 3)
  - Carillo Flores, Antonio (Box 3)
  - Carlip, Vivian (Box 3)
  - Carson, Deane (Box 3)
  - Carson, William J. (Box 3)
  - Carter, Charles F. (Box 3)
  - Ceconi, Tulio Alberto (Box 3)
  - Chandler, Lester V. (Box 3)
  - CIRET - International Contact on Business Tendency Surveys (Box 3)
  - C.C.N.Y. (Box 3)
  - Cole, Charles (Box 3)
  - Colm, Gerhard (Box 3)
  - Committee For Constitutional Government (Box 3)
  - Committee For Economic Development (Box 3)
  - Copeland, Morris Albert (Box 3)
  - Cordier, Andrew Wellington (Box 3)
  - Court, Andrew T. (Box 3)
  - Cox, Reavis (Box 3)
  - Crank letters (Box 3)
  - Crum, N.L. (Box 3)
  - Cuff, Calvin (Box 3)
  - D -misc. (Box 4)
  - Dahlberg, Arthur O. (Box 4)
  - Dale, Ernest (Box 4)
  - Darling, Paul G. (Box 4)
  - Dean, Charles (Box 4)
  - de Chazeau, Melvin G. (Box 4)
  - DeRosa, Paul (Box 4)
  - de Vegh, Paul (Box 4)
  - Dewhurst, J. Frederic (Box 4)
  - Diamond, Harold S. (Box 4)
  - Di Marco, Luis Eugenio (Box 4)
  - Domar, Evsey D. (Box 4)
  - Dreze, Jacques H. (Box 4)
  - du Pont de Nemours Be Company, E. I. (Box 4)
  - Dupriez. Leon H. (Box 4)
  - E - misc. (Box 4)
  - Eccles, Marriner Stoddard (Box 4)
  - Eeker-Racz, Laszlo (Box 4)
  - Eckstein Otto (Box 4)
  - Edel, Matthew David (Box 4)
  - Edelberg, Guillermo S. (Box 4)
  - Edelson, Noel Marc (Box 4)
  - Egle, Walter P. (Box 4)
  - Eisner, Robert (Box 4)
  - Eliasson, Gunnar (Box 4)
  - Elliott, William Yandell (Box 4)
  - Ellis, Howard Sylvester (Box 4)
  - Elson, Robert Anthony (Box 4)
  - Ensley, Grover W. (Box 4)
  - Erpf, Armand Grover (Box 4)
  - F - misc. (Box 4)
  - Fand, David J. (Box 4)
  - Farrell, Crumpton (Box 4)
  - Federal Reserve Board (Box 4)
  - Fellner, William John (Box 4)
  - Ferber, Robert (Box 4)
  - Fernandes, Santiago (Box 4)
  - Figueroa, Eduardo (Box 4)
  - Fine, Donald J. (Box 4)
  - Fisher. Douglas (Box 4)
  - Ford, James W. (Box 4)
  - The Ford Foundation (Box 4)
  - Fossati, Eraldo (Box 4)
  - Fousek, Peter (Box 4)
  - Fox. Bertrand (Box 4)
  - Frazer, William J., Jr. (Box 4)
  - Friley, Charles Edwin (Box 4)
  - Fukesawa, Shigeyuki (Box 4)
  - Furtado'J Celso (Box 4)
  - Fusfeld, David Roland (Box 4)
  - G –misc (Box 5)
  - Gainsburgh, Martin R. (Box 5)
  - Garc1a Torres Hossey, Arturo (Box 5)
  - Garcia Vazquez, Enrique (Box 5)
  - Garcie, Adriano R. (Box 5)
  - Gayer, Arthur D. (Box 5)
  - General Foods Corporation (Box 5)
  - The General Electric Foundation (Box 5)
  - George, Edwin B. (Box 5)
  - George, Walter (Box 5)
  - Gideonse, Harry David (Box 5)
  - Gilbert, Milton (Box 5)
  - Gold, David A. (Box 5)
  - Goldsmith, Raymond W. (Box 5)
  - Goodrich, Carter (Box 5)
  - Gort, Michael (Box 5)
  - Gottlieb, Elias S. (Box 5)
  - Greham, Benjamin (Box 5)
  - Greham, Frank D. (Box 5)
  - Granick, David (Box 5)
  - Grattan, Harley (Box 5)
  - Greenwald, Douglas (Box 5)
  - Greenwood, Hans Peter (Box 5)
  - Griffin, Keith B. (Box 5)
  - Grunwald, Joseph (Box 5)
  - H -misc. (Box 5)
  - Haberler, Gottfried (Box 5)
  - Hagen, Everett E. (Box 5)
  - Baggipavlou, Paul P. (Box 5)
  - Haley, Bernard Francis (Box 5)
  - Hall, Colby D. (Box 5)
  - Hall. Robert A. (Box 5)
  - Hamilton, Earl J. (Box 5)
  - Hansen, Aiyin H. (Box 5)
  - Harcourt, Brace and Company, Inc. (Box 5)
  - Hardy, Charles O. (Box 6)
  - Barmont Elmer M. (Box 6)
  - Barris, Seymour E":' (Box 6)
  - Harriss, C. Lowell (Box 6)
  - Hart, Albert Bushnell (Box 6)
  - Bart, Albert Gailord -personal. &: employment (Box 6)
  - Hart, Albert H. (Box 6)
  - Hart, Ann Elizabeth Webster (Mrs Albert G.) (Box 6)
  - Bart, Elizabeth Haven (Sr. Columba O.S.B.) (Box 6)
  - Hart, Frances Jeannette (Mrs Arthur Burke) (Box 6)
  - Bart, Hastings Hornell (Box 6)
  - Hart, Hornell Norris (Box 6)
  - Hart, Josephine Webster (Mrs Melvin Bristol) (Box 6)
  - Hart, Josephine Newton (Mrs Hastings H.) (Box 6)
  - Hart, Laurance Hastings (Box 6)
  - Hart, Stephen Albert (Box 6)
  - Hart family (Box 6)
  - Harwoodt Edward Browby (Box 6)
  - Hastay, Millard (Box 6)
  - Hawkins t Everett D. (Box 6)
  - Hayer, Friedrich August von (Box 6)
  - Hazelett, Richard (Box 6)
  - Heckscher, August (Box 6)
  - Heller, Walter W. (Box 7)
  - Hicks, Sir John Richard &: Ursula Kathleen Webb Hicks (Box 7)
  - Hirsch, Abraham (Box 7)
  - Hoftman, Paul G. (Box 7)
  - Hoffmann, Charles (Box 7)
  - Holt, Charles G. (Box 7)
  - Homan, Paul T. (Box 7)
  - Hooft-Welvaars, Maria (Box 7)
  - Hooley, Richard W. (Box 7)
  - Hoover, Calvin Bryce (Box 7)
  - Horvath, Janos (Box 7)
  - I - misc. (Box 7)
  - Ifo-Institut fur Wirtschaftsforschung (Box 7)
  - Iglesias. Enrique V. (Box 7)
  - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences (Box 7)
  - J –misc. (Box 7)
  - Jackson of Lodsworth, Barbara Mary Ward Jackson, Baroness (Box 7)
  - Jacoby, Nell H. (Box 7)
  - Jaffe, Abraham J. (Box 7)
  - Japanese acquaintances (Box 7)
  - Jesness, O.B. (Box 7)
  - Johnson, Shirley B. (Box 7)
  - Joint Economic Committee -U.S. Congress (Box 7)
  - Jones, Homer (Box 7)
  - Jones, Robert J. (Box 7)
  - Jordan, Carl P. (Box 7)
  - Jordan, James E., Jr. (Box 7)
  - Jouvenel. des Ursins, Baron Bertrand de (Box 7)
  - Juster, Thomas (Box 7)
  - K - misc. (Box 8)
  - Kachi, Yukio (Box 8)
  - Kahn, Baron (Box 8)
  - Kahn, Richard Ferdinand (Box 8)
  - Kaldor, Nicholas Kaldor, Baron (Box 8)
  - Katona, George (Box 8)
  - Kazanjian Economics Foundation, Inc., The Calvin K. (Box 8)
  - Kenen, Peter B. (Box 8)
  - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald (Box 8)
  - Kim, Sungwoo (Box 8)
  - Kim, Young Chin (Box 8)
  - Kindleberger, Charles P. (Box 8)
  - Kirk, Grayson (Box 8)
  - Klein, Laurence R. (Box 8)
  - Klusev, Nikola M. (Box 8)
  - Knight, Frank Hyneman (Box 8)
  - Kolin, Marshall (Box 8)
  - Kosh, David A. (Box 8)
  - Kuznats, Simon (Box 8)
  - L - misc. (Box 8)
  - Lancaster, Kelvin (Box 8)
  - Lange, Oscar (Box 8)
  - Langum, John (Box 8)
  - Lazarsteld, Paul Felix (Box 8)
  - Leland, Simeon Elbridge (Box 8)
  - Leontiet, Wassily W. (Box 8)
  - Lerner, Abba P. (Box 8)
  - Lett, Nathaniel H. (Box 8)
  - Levarie, Siegmund (Box 8)
  - Levin, Harvey J. (Box 8)
  - Lieblein, Julius (Box 8)
  - Lindahl, Erik (Box 8)
  - Lindley, Ernest K. (Box 8)
  - Lovell, Michael C. (Box 8)
  - Luna, Ricardo (Box 8)
  - Lutz, Friedrich A. (Box 8)
  - M - misc. (Box 9)
  - McFarland, Earl L, Jr. (Box 9)
  - Macblup, Fritz (Box 9)
  - Madariaga, Salvadorde (Box 9)
  - Marcos-Yacaman, Jesus (Box 9)
  - Marget, Arthur W. (Box 9)
  - MarscMk, Jacob (Box 9)
  - Massad, Carlos (Box 9)
  - Mateo, Fernando (Box 9)
  - Mayer, Thomas (Box 9)
  - McFa.rland, Earl L., Jr. (Box 9)
  - McLaurin, Dunbar S. (Box 9)
  - Means, Gardiner C. (Box 9)
  - Meisser, Hans (Box 9)
  - Mendelson, M. (Box 9)
  - Meyer, Gerhard (Box 9)
  - Meyer, Michael (Box 9)
  - Meyer, Richard H. (Box 9)
  - Mikesell, Raymond F. (Box 9)
  - Miller, F.D. (Box 9)
  - Millis, H.A. (Box 9)
  - Mills, Frederick Cecil (Box 9)
  - Minsky, Hyman P. (Box 9)
  - Modigliani, Franco (Box 9)
  - Moline. Silva, Sergio (Box 9)
  - Moore, Geoffrey H. (Box 9)
  - Morse, Dean (Box 9)
  - Morton, Walter A. (Box 9)
  - Mosak, Jacob L. (Box 9)
  - Murphy, Evelyn (Box 9)
  - Murray, Roger F. (Box 9)
  - Murray, William G. (Box 9)
  - Musgrave, Richard A. (Box 9)
  - Myers, Betty &: Paul (Box 9)
  - Myers, Howard B. (Box 9)
  - N - Misc. (Box 9)
  - Nagel, Ernest (Box 9)
  - Nakamura, James 1. (Box 9)
  - New York Times (Box 9)
  - Nicholls, William H. (Box 9)
  - Nixon, Richard Milhous (Box 9)
  - Nourse, Edwin G. (Box 9)
  - Nowak, Norman D. (Box 9)
  - Nuemark, Fritz (Box 9)
  - Oldman, Oliver (Box 9)
  - Oliveira, Manuel J.F. (Box 9)
  - O'Neal, Edward A. (Box 9)
  - Opie, Redvers (Box 9)
  - P –misc. (Box 10)
  - Paish, F.W. (Box 10)
  - Paradiso, Louis J. (Box 10)
  - Parsky, Gerald L. (Box 10)
  - Patton, James G. (Box 10)
  - Paul, Randolph E. (Box 10)
  - Pechman, Joseph A. (Box 10)
  - Pelaez, Carlos M. (Box 10)
  - Perroux, Francois (Box 10)
  - Petrecolla, Alberto O. (Box 10)
  - Pfaff, Martin (Box 10)
  - Pierson, John H.G. (Box 10)
  - Pikler, Andrew (Box 10)
  - Plumptre, A.F.W. (Box 10)
  - Polachek, S. (Box 10)
  - Pontecorvo, Giulio (Box 10)
  - Prager, Jonas (Box 10)
  - Prebisch, Raul. (Box 10)
  - Probst, George (Box 10)
  - Proxmire, William (Box 10)
  - Publishing: A -Z (Box 10)
  - Q ~ misc. (Box 10)
  - R -misc. (Box 11)
  - Ramos, Joseph (Box 11)
  - Randall, Laura (Box 11)
  - Redfield, Robert (Box 11)
  - Reischauer, Robert D. (Box 11)
  - Renfro, Newton E. (Box 11)
  - Ricker, Elinor (Box 11)
  - The Ripon Society of New York, Inc. (Box 11)
  - Robertson, A. Willis (Box 11)
  - Robinson, Patricia Rawlins (Box 11)
  - Robinson, Roland I. (Box 11)
  - Rosa, Robert V. (Box 11)
  - Rosen, George (Box 11)
  - Rosenbluth, Robert (Box 11)
  - Rousseas, Stephen W. (Box 11)
  - Rufting, Kenenth G. (Box 11)
  - Ruggles, Richard & Nancy Dunlap Ruggles (Box 11)
  - S -misc. (Box 11)
  - Sachs, Reynold M. (Box 11)
  - Saini, Krishan G. (Box 11)
  - Scheyven, Baudouin Renato (Box 11)
  - Schlckele, Rainer (Box 11)
  - Sclmltz, Henry (Box 11)
  - Schultz, Theodore W. (Box 11)
  - Schumpeter, Joseph A. (Box 11)
  - Schweitzer, Arthur (Box 11)
  - Segura, Edilberto L. (Box 11)
  - Seltzer, Lawrence E. (Box 11)
  - Senior, Cristobal D. (Box 11)
  - Shackle, George Lennox Sharman (Box 12)
  - Shaffer, Edward H. (Box 12)
  - Shay, Robert P. (Box 12)
  - Shebanov, Vladimir Al.eksandrovich (Box 12)
  - Shere, Louis (Box 12)
  - Shoup, Carl Sumner (Box 12)
  - Siegman, Charles J. (Box 12)
  - Simons, Henry C. (Box 12)
  - Smith, Helen &: Tom. (Box 12)
  - Smith, Henry Cassorte (Box 12)
  - Smithies, Arthur (Box 12)
  - Southard, Frank. A., Jr. (Box 12)
  - Sowell, Thomas (Box 12)
  - Steed, L. Douglas (Box 12)
  - Stein, Herbert (Box 12)
  - Steinberg, Charles (Box 12)
  - Stevelman, Daniel (Box 12)
  - Stevens, Denis (Box 12)
  - Strasma, John (Box 12)
  - Strigel, Werner H. (Box 12)
  - Strong, Frank R. (Box 12)
  - Stukart, Gregorio (Box 12)
  - Suarez, James Michael (Box 12)
  - Sumberg. Theodore A. (Box 12)
  - Sweezy, Alan (Box 12)
  - T -misc. (Box 12)
  - Tarasov, Helen (Box 12)
  - Taylor, W. Bayard (Box 12)
  - Taylor, Horace (Box 12)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association (Box 12)
  - Theil, Henri (Box 12)
  - Thorn, Richard S. (Box 12)
  - Tichy, Gunther (Box 12)
  - Tinbergen, Jan (Box 12)
  - Tintner, Gerhard (Box 12)
  - Toan, Cao (Box 12)
  - Tolles, N. Arnold (Box 12)
  - U -misc. (Box 12)
  - Varghese, M.P. (Box 12)
  - Vickrey, William S. (Box 12)
  - Vieg, John A. (Box 12)
  - Villanueva, Javier (Box 12)
  - Villard, Henry H. (Box 12)
  - Villarzu R., Juan (Box 12)
  - Viner, Jacob (Box 12)
  - Volcker, Paul. A. (Box 12)
  - Volmar, Gustavo S. (Box 12)
  - W -misc. (Box 13)
  - Wadsted, Otto G. (Box 13)
  - Wa.gley, Charles (Box 13)
  - Walker, Mabel (Box 13)
  - Wallicht Henry C. (Box 13)
  - Warburton, Clark (Box 13)
  - Warrington, Howard M. (Box 13)
  - Wasson, R. Gordon (Box 13)
  - Weymack, W. W. (Box 13)
  - Webber, Howard (Box 13)
  - Webster, Bethuel M. (Box 13)
  - Wendel, Helmut (Box 13)
  - White, Harry D. (Box 13)
  - Wilbur, C. Martin (Box 13)
  - Willenbrock, Mildred White (Box 13)
  - Williams, Alfred H. (Box 13)
  - Willoughby, George (Box 13)
  - Wirth, Louis (Box 13)
  - Woitrin, Michel (Box 13)
  - Wolte, A.B. (Box 13)
  - Wright, David McCord (Box 13)
  - Wright, Lloyd I. (Box 13)
  - Y –misc. (Box 13)
  - Yasuda, Nobuichi (Box 13)
  - Yntema., Theodore O. (Box 13)
  - Young, Ralph A. (Box 13)
  - Z –misc. (Box 13)
  - Zottmann, Luiz. (Box 13)
  - Zunige., Raphael. Alberto (Box 13)
  - Misc. unidentified (Box 13)
- Series III:Hart Manuscripts
  - 1913-1932 (Box 14)
  - 1933-1934 (Box 15)
  - 1934-1935 (Box 16)
  - 1936 (Box 17)
  - 1937-1941 (Box 18)
  - 1942-1943 (Box 19)
  - 1944-1945 (Box 20)
  - 1945-1946 (Box 21)
  - 1946-1948 (Box 22)
  - 1949-1951 (Box 23)
  - 1951-J953 (Box 24)
  - 1954-1956 (Box 25)
  - 1956-1958 (Box 26)
  - 1958-1961 (Box 27)
  - 1961-1963 (Box 28)
  - 1964 (Box 29)
  - 1964-1965 (Box 30)
  - 1965-1966 (Box 31)
  - 1966-1967 (Box 32)
  - 1968-1869 (Box 33)
  - 1969-1973 (Box 34)
  - 1974-1975 (Box 35)
  - 1976-1978 (Box 36)
- Series IV: Papers of other economists that influenced Hart
  - A-B (Box 37)
  - C (Box 38)
  - D-E (Box 39)
  - F (Box 49)
  - G-Harris, L. (Box 41)
  - Harris, S. E.-Hi (Box 42)
  - Ho-Kal (Box 43)
  - Kan-Ku (Box 44)
  - L-Mad (Box 45)
  - Mar-Meeting(l) (Box 46)
  - Meeting(2)-Mu (Box 47)
  - N-Pe (Box 48)
  - Ph-Sha (Box 49)
  - Sho-V (Box 50)
  - W (Box 51)
  - Commodity Currency (Box 52-54)
  - Chile: (Box 55)
    - General Papers, August 1961-February 1962 (Box 55)
    - Subject File A-Le (Box 55)
    - General Papers (Box 56)
    - Subject File Le-Z (Box 56)
    - Tax Reform, August 1961-May 1963 (Box 57)
    - Tax Reform (Box 58)
    - Subject File (Box 58)
  - Costa Rica, Mexico (Box 59)
  - Teaching Materials (Box 60)
    - Learning 1927-36 (Box 60)
    - Chicago J932-40 Iowa (Box 61)
    - Columbia (Box 62)
    - Columbia (cont.) 1946-61 (Box 63)
    - Non-Columbia 1946-1975 (Box 64)
    - Non-Columbia 1976-80 (Box 65)
    - Columbia 1950-68 (Box 66)
    - Columbia 1969-73 (Box 67)
    - Columbia 1974-78 (Box 68)
    - Student papers and dissertations, Atlee-Gold (Box 69)
    - Student papers and dissertations, Gros-Juster (Box 70)
    - Student papers and dissertations, Karcik-Pelaez (Box 71)
    - Student papers and dissertations, Rosenbaum-Tharp (Box 72)
    - Student papers and dissertations, Villanueva-Zottmann (Box 73)
    - Student papers and dissertations, Bellan-Kim (Box 74)
    - Student papers and dissertations, Lee-Ruffing (Box 75)
    - Student papers and dissertations, Sachs-Wright (Box 76)
    - Student papers and dissertations, Wright-Zoolman (Box 77)
- Series V: Printed Materials
  - A (Box 78)
  - B (Box 79)
  - Printed Materials 1933-1958 (Box 80)
  - Printed Materials 1959-1970 (Box 81)